Guide to the Frederic Ewen Papers TAM.277
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
- Series VII: Research Notes, undated
  - Subseries A: Proper Names, undated
    - Marx, Karl (2 of 4), undated (Box 7, Folder 23)
    - Marx, Karl (3 of 4), undated (Box 7, Folder 24)
    - Marx, Karl (4 of 4), undated (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - Milton, John, undated (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - Petöfi, Sandor, undated (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - Pushkin, Aleksandr, undated (Box 8, Folder 4)
    - Seigel, Jerrold- Marx's Fate: The Shape of a Life, undated (Box 8, Folder 5)
    - Rossetti, William Michael, undated (Box 8, Folder 6)
    - Ruskin, John, undated (Box 8, Folder 7)
    - Somervell, D. C.- English Thought in the 19th Century, undated (Box 8, Folder 8)
    - Tolstoy, Leo, undated (Box 8, Folder 9)
    - Turgenev, Ivan Sergeyevich (1 of 2), undated (Box 8, Folder 10)
    - Turgenev, Ivan Sergeyevich (2 of 2), undated (Box 8, Folder 11)
    - Verlaine- Confessions, undated (Box 8, Folder 12)
    - Wagner, Richard, undated (Box 8, Folder 13)
    - Wilde, Oscar, undated (Box 8, Folder 14)
    - Wordsworth, William, undated (Box 8, Folder 15)
    - Zola, Emile (1 of 2), undated (Box 8, Folder 16)
    - Zola, Emile (2 of 2), undated (Box 8, Folder 17)
    - Zweig, Arnold, undated (Box 8, Folder 18)
  - Subseries B: Geographic Location, undated
    This subseries concern authors who are significant to the region.
    - 1848 France (1 of 2), undated (Box 8, Folder 19)
    - 1848 France (2 of 2), undated (Box 8, Folder 20)
    - 1848 General, undated (Box 8, Folder 21)
    - 1848 Germany, Austria, Italy, Hungary (1 of 2), undated (Box 8, Folder 22)
    - 1848 Germany, Austria, Italy, Hungary (2 of 2), undated (Box 8, Folder 23)
    - Austria: Grillparzer, Hebbel, Lanau (1 of 2), undated (Box 9, Folder 1)
    - Austria: Grillparzer, Hebbel, Lanau (2 of 2), undated (Box 9, Folder 2)
    - Denmark, undated (Box 9, Folder 3)
    - France, undated (Box 9, Folder 4)
    - Germany: Buchner, Freiligrath, Herwegh, Weirth (1 of 3), undated (Box 9, Folder 5)
    - Germany: Buchner, Freiligrath, Herwegh, Weirth (2 of 3), undated (Box 9, Folder 6)
    - Germany: Buchner, Freiligrath, Herwegh, Weirth (3 of 3), undated (Box 9, Folder 7)
    - Germany: Heinrich Heine, undated (Box 9, Folder 8)
    - Norway, undated (Box 9, Folder 9)
    - Russia (1 of 2), undated (Box 9, Folder 10)
    - Russia (2 of 2), undated (Box 9, Folder 11)
    - Russia: Herzen, Belinsky, Stankiewich, Petroshevsky, Dostoyevski, Shevchenko (1of 2), undated (Box 9, Folder 12)
    - Russia: Herzen, Belinsky, Stankiewich, Petroshevsky, Dostoyevski, Shevchenko (2 of 2), undated (Box 9, Folder 13)
  - Subseries C: Subjects, undated
    - Absolute Bourgeoise, undated (Box 9, Folder 14)
    - Ancient: Abbé Gregoire, Frederic II, undated (Box 9, Folder 15)
    - Ancient: Aeschylus, Agamemnon, undated (Box 9, Folder 16)
    - Ancient: Aristophanes, undated (Box 9, Folder 17)
    - Ancient: Art of Comedy, Greek Comedy, undated (Box 9, Folder 18)
    - Ancient: Drama: Mayan, Egyptian, undated (Box 9, Folder 19)
    - Ancient: Euripides, undated (Box 9, Folder 20)
    - Ancient: Hölderlin, undated (Box 9, Folder 21)
    - Ancient: Original Material: Greek Tragedy/Comedy, undated (Box 9, Folder 22)
    - Ancient: Project Maters of the Word, Poets' Landscape, undated (Box 9, Folder 23)
    - Ancient: Sophocles, Oedipus, undated (Box 9, Folder 24)
    - Ancient: Spinoza, undated (Box 9, Folder 25)
    - The Drama: 18th Century, Chronologies, Political/Social Thought, Pastoral, undated (Box 10, Folder 1)
    - The Drama: Drama Chronology 1660-1750, Drama 18th c second half, Middle Class Drama, undated (Box 10, Folder 2)
    - The Drama: Addison, Akenside, Arbuthnot, undated (Box 10, Folder 3)
    - The Drama: Pierre Bayle, Beaumarchais, Biography, William Blake, undated (Box 10, Folder 4)
    - The Drama: Carey, Mrs. Centlivre, Cowper, Crabbe, Defoe, Deism, Diderot, undated (Box 10, Folder 5)
    - The Drama: Farquahar, Fielding, Gay, Gibbon, undated (Box 10, Folder 6)
    - The Drama: Godwin, Goldon, Goldsmith, Gothicism, undated (Box 10, Folder 7)
    - The Drama: History and Historical Writing, Holbach, Holborg, Samuel Johnson, Methodism, Montesquieu, undated (Box 10, Folder 8)
    - The Drama: Thomas Paine, Periodical Essay, Pope, Pre-Romanticism, Reynolds, Richardson, undated (Box 10, Folder 9)
    - The Drama: Rousseau, Shaftesbury, Shakespeare, Sheridan, Sterne, Swift, undated (Box 10, Folder 10)
    - The Drama: Thomson, Voltaire, Mary Wollstonecraft, undated (Box 10, Folder 11)
    - European Literature, undated (Box 10, Folder 12)
    - French Poetry, undated (Box 10, Folder 13)
    - Industrial Revolution and English Fiction, undated (Box 10, Folder 14)
    - The Jew in Literature: in Drama, undated (Box 10, Folder 15)
    - The Jew in Literature: in Novel, undated (Box 10, Folder 16)
    - The Jew in Literature: in Mystics, undated (Box 10, Folder 17)
    - The Jew in Literature: The Yellow Badge, by Hofmann/Zweig, undated (Box 10, Folder 18)
    - Literary Criticism: 18th Century, Renaissance-France, England, Italy, undated (Box 10, Folder 19)
    - Literary Criticism: American Literary Criticism, 17th Century English Literary Criticism, undated (Box 10, Folder 20)
    - Literary Criticism: Aristotle, Plato, Roman Criticism, undated (Box 10, Folder 21)
    - Literary Criticism: Coleridge, undated (Box 10, Folder 22)
    - Literary Criticism: Neo Classicism, undated (Box 10, Folder 23)
    - Literary Criticism: Poetry and Painting 18th Century, Lessing, undated (Box 10, Folder 24)
    - Literary Criticism: Pragmatic Criticism, Surrealism, Humanism, Realism, undated (Box 10, Folder 25)
    - Literary Criticism: Theories of Literary Criticism, undated (Box 10, Folder 26)
    - Literary Criticism: Theory of Literature, Literary Trends England, Psychoanalysis, Sociological, undated (Box 10, Folder 27)
    - Miscellaneous Bibliographic Notes (1 of 5), undated (Box 10, Folder 28)
    - Miscellaneous Bibliographic Notes (2 of 5), undated (Box 10, Folder 29)
    - Miscellaneous Bibliographic Notes (3 of 5), undated (Box 10, Folder 30)
    - Miscellaneous Bibliographic Notes (4 of 5), undated (Box 11, Folder 1)
    - Miscellaneous Bibliographic Notes/Vocabulary Translations (5 of 5), undated (Box 11, Folder 2)
    - Romanticism, undated (Box 11, Folder 3)
    - Romanticism: Beethoven, Byron, undated (Box 11, Folder 4)
    - Romanticism: Emerson, Hawthorne, St. Pierre, de Stael, and German Theatre, undated (Box 11, Folder 5)
    - Romanticism: Historical Novel, French Romantics of 1830, Literary Theories, undated (Box 11, Folder 6)
    - Romanticism: Henry James, undated (Box 11, Folder 7)
    - Romanticism: Keats, Leist, Lamb, Lockhart, undated (Box 11, Folder 8)
    - Romanticism: Herman Melville, undated (Box 11, Folder 9)
    - Romanticism: Schiller, Shelley, undated (Box 11, Folder 10)
    - Romanticism: The Theory of Tragedy, undated (Box 11, Folder 11)
    - Romanticism: Mark Twain, undated (Box 11, Folder 12)
    - Russian Poetry Translations, undated (Box 11, Folder 13)
    - Shakespeare (1 of 5), undated (Box 11, Folder 14)
    - Shakespeare (2 of 5), undated (Box 11, Folder 15)
    - Shakespeare (3 of 5), undated (Box 11, Folder 16)
    - Shakespeare (4 of 5), undated (Box 11, Folder 17)
    - Shakespeare (5 of 5), undated (Box 11, Folder 18)
    - World Literature Themes (1 of 5), undated (Box 11, Folder 19)
    - World Literature Themes (2 of 5), undated (Box 11, Folder 20)
    - World Literature Themes (3 of 5), undated (Box 11, Folder 21)
    - World Literature Themes (4 of 5), undated (Box 12, Folder 1)
    - World Literature Themes (5 of 5), undated (Box 12, Folder 2)
    - World Literature Themes: 17th Century, undated (Box 12, Folder 3)
    - World Literature Themes: Academics of Art, undated (Box 12, Folder 4)
    - World Literature Themes: Cervantes, Lope de Vega, undated (Box 12, Folder 5)
    - World Literature Themes: Chronology Thought Documents, undated (Box 12, Folder 6)
    - World Literature Themes: French, undated (Box 12, Folder 7)
    - World Literature Themes: Historical Background, Political/Social Movements, undated (Box 12, Folder 8)
    - World Literature Themes: Puritanism, undated (Box 12, Folder 9)
    - World Literature Themes: Restoration, undated (Box 12, Folder 10)
    - World Literature Themes: Scientific Background, undated (Box 12, Folder 11)
    - Alphabetical Files on 3X5 cards (1 of 4) A-B, undated (Box 12, Folder 12)
    - Alphabetical Files on 3X5 cards (2 of 4) C-H, undated (Box 12, Folder 13)
    - Alphabetical Files on 3X5 cards (3 of 4) I-N, undated (Box 12, Folder 14)
    - Alphabetical Files on 3X5 cards (4 of 4) O-Z, undated (Box 12, Folder 15)
    - Chronology File on 3X5 cards (1 of 4), undated (Box 12, Folder 16)
    - Chronology File on 3X5 cards (2 of 4), undated (Box 12, Folder 17)
    - Chronology File on 3X5 cards (3 of 4), undated (Box 12, Folder 18)
    - Chronology File on 3X5 cards (4 of 4), undated (Box 12, Folder 19)
- Series VIII: Subject Files, 1921-1984
  This series contains a set of files on various topics of interest to Ewen particularly his research and teaching in literature. The files include comments and papers on Brecht, Tolstoy and other authors. Also included are grade books and files on various universities Ewen was connected with.
  - Berliner Ensemble, 1965-1966 (Box 12, Folder 20)
  - Book Jackets, undated (Box 12, Folder 21)
  - Book Pictures, undated (Box 12, Folder 22)
  - Brecht, Bertolt (1 of 2), undated (Box 12, Folder 23)
  - Brecht, Bertolt (2 of 2), undated (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - Brecht Book, 1967-1971 (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - Brecht Book Permissions, 1966-1967 (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - Brecht Book Promotion, 1967-1968 (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - Brecht Book Reviews, 1967-1969 (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - Brecht Book Reviews (German), undated (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - Brooklyn College and Board of Education, 1941 (Box 13, Folder 7)
  - Brooklyn College- Committee on the Improvement of Teaching, undated (Box 13, Folder 8)
  - Brooklyn College- Faculty Advisor Marx Society, 1949 (Box 13, Folder 9)
  - Brooklyn College- President Gideonse, 1941-1949 (Box 13, Folder 10)
  - Brooklyn College- Professorship Papers, 1938-1952 (Box 13, Folder 11)
  - College Newsletter, 1940-1941 (Box 13, Folder 12)
  - Contemporary Theatre, 1964-1965 (Box 13, Folder 13)
  - Dictionary, undated (Box 13, Folder 14)
  - Grade Books, 1923-1930 (Box 13, Folder 15)
  - Grade Books, 1932-1939 (Box 13, Folder 17)
  - Grade Books, 1940-1950 (Box 13, Folder 18)
  - Education Defense Bulletin, 1940-1941 (Box 13, Folder 19)
  - Faustus, Johann, undated (Box 13, Folder 20)
  - Heine, Heinrich: portfolio with postcards and facsimiles from Dusseldorf in oversize box, undated (Box 13, Folder 21)
  - Heroic Imaginaytion- Book Reviews, 1984 (Box 13, Folder 22)
  - Juilliard School, 1967-1970 (Box 13, Folder 23)
  - Master Institute, 1950s-1960s (Box 13, Folder 24)
  - Obituaries, 1980s (Box 13, Folder 25)
  - Portrait of the Artist, Magic Mountain, 1963-1966 (Box 13, Folder 26)
  - Programs (1 of 2), undated (Box 13, Folder 27)
  - Programs (2 of 2), undated (Box 13, Folder 28)
  - Public Programs-Round Table Review/Drama Tours, undated (Box 13, Folder 29)
  - Public Programs-Humanities Institute, Brooklyn College, 1980s (Box 13, Folder 30)
  - Randolph, John, undated (Box 13, Folder 31)
  - Rosten, Norman, undated (Box 13, Folder 32)
  - Schappes, Morris, 1941-1944 (Box 13, Folder 33)
  - The Shamrock Company, 1961-1962 (Box 13, Folder 34)
  - Teachers Union, 1940s (Box 13, Folder 35)
  - Theater Programs (1 of 2), undated (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - Theater Programs (2 of 2), undated (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - Thesaurus, undated (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - Tolstoy, Leo, 1960 (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - Weizmann, Chaim (1 of 2), undated (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - Weizmann, Chaim (2 of 2), undated (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - Wershba, Joseph, undated (Box 14, Folder 7)
  - Yeshiva University, 1964 (Box 14, Folder 8)
- Series IX: Photographs, 1940s-1980s
  This series contains photographs collected and used by Ewen in publications. It includes family photographs, photographs of Brecht stage scenes for his book, Bertolt Brecht: His Life, His Art, and His Times, and portraits of Ewen, John Randolph and Sarah Cunningham. The bulk of the photographs contain headshots of actors, including Lois de Banzie, Elinor Bassescu, Robert Burr, Ludwig Donath, Judith Doty, Fredi Dundee, Joyce Ebert, Michael Ebert, Jack Gilford, Mark Gordon, Suzanne Granfield, Lucy Greene, Marvin Hayes, Madhur Jaffrey, Saeed Jaffrey, Michael Jolan, Harriet Laine, Lenore Loveman, Marya Manning, Maurine Marlowe, Beatrice Mauley, Joanna Merlin, Dino Narizzano, Marjorie Nelson, Patricia O'Connell, Dina Paisner, Fred Pinkard, Maggie de Priest, Joe Silver, Paul Sparer, Martin Wolfson, and Janis Young.
  - Brecht Book, 1960s (Box 14, Folder 9)
  - Family Photographs, 1940s-1980s (Box 14, Folder 10)
  - Frederic Ewen, 1950s-1970s (Box 14, Folder 11)
  - Frederic Ewen, 1960s-1980s (Box 14, Folder 12)
  - Head Shots: A-K, 1960s (Box 14, Folder 13)
  - Head Shots: L-Z, 1960s (Box 14, Folder 14)
  - Photographs of John Randolph and Sarah Cunningham, 1960s-1986 (Box 14, Folder 15)